A Guide to the William Ingham Papers, 1945-2013: SC 0002
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
- Series 3: Research and Scholarship, 1945-2013
  - Cosmic Perspectives Publishers Correspondence, 1980-1983 (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - Cosmic Perspectives Reviewer Comments, 1982 (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - Cosmology, Early 1970's (Box 46, Folder 17)
  - Creeping Flow around a Sphere, 2001 (Box 46, Folder 18)
  - CS 449 Notebook, undated (Box 46, Folder 19)
  - Cyclotron Radiation, 1975-1976 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - d'Espagnat's "The Quantum Theory and Reality," Shimony's "The Reality of the Quantum World", 1979, 1988 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Daily News-Record, Montpelier Archaeology Article, 2006 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Davis & Park's No Way: The Nature of the Impossible (Intro & Table of Contents), 1988 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Degree Datatables, figures & spreadsheets, 1995-1998 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - The Deuteron (Simple illustrative models), 1981 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Development of the Atomic Bomb, 1988-2001 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Dimensional Analysis, 2001 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Discover, 1998 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Div, Grad, Curl, etc. (Schey, Purcell), 1992 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Dobzhanksky, et al. Evolution (excerpts), 1977 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Doppler Effect (Newtonian), 1983 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Double Pendulum Articles, 1994-2004 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Double Radio Sources, 1973-1974 (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - Drag Coefficient for a sphere (Chow, LeMehaute, Tritton, Landon, & Lipshitz), 1983 (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - Paul Durbi, "A Guide to the Culture of Science, Technology and Medicine", 1984 (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - "Education Reform for the 70s", 1972 (Box 47, Folder 17)
  - Albert Einstein: Image and Impact, 2004 (Box 47, Folder 18)
  - Einstein Research/AIP, 2006 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Eisberg-Lerner Text Review, 1978-1982 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Eisberg/Resnick Notes, 1993 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Electrostatic, 1986-1988 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Electrostatic Surprise, 1985-1986 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Emails, News Clippings, Ads & Notes, 1996-2001 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - ERC/Keller Plan papers, 1971-1976 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Examples for Linear Algebra & its Appl'n to QM, 1984 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Examples from Computer Algebra Recipes, undated (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Excerpts from papers on hydrogen ion reactions, 1976-1977 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Exploring Black Holes, 2008 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Exploring Black Holes Correspondence, 2008 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - External Flows (Past Symmetric Objects) & Drag, Creeping, Newton, etc., 1981-2001 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Fan Mountain (Randy Fear), 1978-1979 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Feynman Sketches/Graph reflow pastcyclinder, undated (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Richard P. Feynman, "The Value of Science", 1947-1955 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Richard P. Feynman, "The Value of Science", undated (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Figures & Captions, Ch.1., undated (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Finished Constellation Maps, 1978-1979 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - The Fires of Alchemy, 1988 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Fluid Circulation, Kelvin's Theorem, & Vortices, 2001 (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Fluid Dynamics, 1994-2002 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Fluid Statics: Pascal's Law, Atmos Profiles. Tides, 1999-2002 (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Follow the Bouncing Bulls, 1993 (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Forensics/Consulting, 1986-1988 (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Forms for Sec. III Tables, 1982-1983 (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - French and Taylor, "Limitation of Proper Length in Special Relativity", 1983 (Box 49, Folder 18)
  - French & Taylor Paper I, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 19)
  - French & Taylor Paper II, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Fundamentals of F.D. Continuity eq also (Newton to Navier-Stokes), undated (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Gaussiau Integrals, 1984 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - General Physics: Fluids, Waves & Sounds including Vector Analysis, undated (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - General Research Materials, 2005-2007 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Giffen & Marqfino, 2004 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - A Glossary of Terms in Statistical Physics, 1976 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - GoCritical, 1977 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - God & The Astronomers (Reading List Talk), 1987 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Goldstein Notes, undated (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Goldstein Problem Solutions, Ch. 1-5, 1985 (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Grab Bag Problems, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Gravitational Systems, 1975 (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - "Gravitea", 1979-1980 (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Griffiths Solutions, Ch.1-3, 1992 (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - Griffiths Solutions, Ch. 4-8, 1992 (Box 50, Folder 16)
  - Harrison's "Masks of the Universe," Gingerich's "The Galileo Affair", 1982, 1985 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Harrisonburg Weather Records, 2001 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Doug las Hartree, The Calculation of Atomic Structures, 1957 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - HP-9820A Programs Documentation, 1978-1979 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - History of Dynamic Systems & Chaos, undated (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - History of Science background (Folder 1 of 3), 2006 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - History of Science background (Folder 2 of 3), 2006 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - History of Science background (Folder 3 of 3), 2006 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - History of Science biographies, undated (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - History of Science PowerPoint Slides, 2004-2005 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - History of Science Slides, 2005 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - History of Science Society, 2003-2008, undated (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - History of Science Timelines, 1976, undated (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Holt Physics Review Phase I, 2003-2004 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Holt Physics Review Phase II, 2004 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Hotfile, 1983-2009 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - HRW Holt Science & Technology Review, 2003 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Important Dates & Blank Timelines (Folder 1 of 2), undated (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Important Dates & Blank Timelines (Folder 2 of 2), undated (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Industrial Revolution, 1997 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Ingham, Brecher, & Wasserman "On the Origin of Continuum Polarization in White Dwarfs" Reprints, 1976 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Ingham & Morrison Symmetry Reprints, 1975 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Ingham, et. Al., "Simplified Theory of Ion Source", 1978 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Interstellar Molecules, Life on Earth, 1980 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Inviscid Flow (Tritton, Paterson), undated (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Ionization Rate Computation, 1977 (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - IPEDS Degree Data, 1995 (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Isenberg & Chomet's Physics Experiments and Projects for Students, 1994 (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - James Madison Center Publications, undated (Box 53, Folder 11)
  - The James Madison Journal, 1979 (Box 53, Folder 12)
  - Joss, Wind Notes, 1976-1980 (Box 53, Folder 13)
  - Kinematics of Fluids, Eulenan V. Lograngian, Divergence, Relevant Vector Calculus, 1979 (Box 53, Folder 14)
  - Kinetic Theory of Gases, Thermodynamics, & Transport, 1999-2000 (Box 53, Folder 15)
  - Kites et al, 2002 (Box 53, Folder 16)
  - Kleinmann, Brecher, & Ingham, "Infrared Emission From A0620-00" reprints, 1976 (Box 53, Folder 17)
  - R.F. Knacke's Solutions to Problems to accompany F. Reif's Fundamentals of Statistical and Thermal Physics, 1965 (Box 53, Folder 18)
  - Richard T. Kouzes "Interior Model of a Star", undated (Box 53, Folder 19)
  - Kreyszig Exercises, 1977 (Box 53, Folder 20)
  - Kreyszig Solutions, 1987 (Box 53, Folder 21)
  - Lai, Rubin, Krempl Problem Solutions, 1986 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Landmarks of Science, Series I & II, 1984-1985 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - James J. Leary/William H. Ingham, "E&MC2: An Intuitive Derivation", 2005-2008 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Least-Time & Related, 1992 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Lederman's "The Value of Fundamental Science," Szent-Gyergi's "Lost in the Twentieth Century", 1965, 1984 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Letters and Other Writings of James Madison, Vol. III (1865), undated (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Leung, Collier, Marshall et. Al. "Characteristics of a Multidipole Ion Source", 1977 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Leung, et. Al., "Characteristics of a multidipole ion source", 1978 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Leung, Kribel, & Taylor "Measurement of the Effective Mean Free Paths of Primary Electrons", 1976 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - LHR Assorted Articles, 1947, 1987-1988, 1995 (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Liboff Problem Solutions, Ch. 6-9, 1984 (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - Liboff Text Notes (Folder 1 of 3), 2012 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Liboff Text Notes (Folder 2 of 3), 2012 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Liboff Text Notes (Folder 3 of 3), 2012 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Library of Congress Material, 2010-2012 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Life at Small Scale, undated (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Liggett & Caughey text & related, 2001 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Linear Algebra and is application to QM, 1984 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - List of terms for Fluid Mechanics, 1999 (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Literary References for Cosmic Perspectives, undated (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - Dolley Madison Letters, 2009 (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - James Madison Eulogy Research, 2006 (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - James Madison Letters, undated (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - James Madison Notes, 2007 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Madison Plasma Group (Notes on Meeting), 1977 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - James Madison Research, 2004-2009 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - James Madison Research, 2006 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - James Madison Timeline, undated (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - James Madison and Science Research, 2004-2009 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Madison Voiceover Project, 2008-2009 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Manhattan Project: The Atomic Bomb from The Nuclear Almanac, 1984 (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - Maple Notes, 2002 (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - Marks, Nuland, Struik, Harre History of Science Reading Notes, 1983-1984 (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - Massess, Excess, Deficits: A Formulary P338, 335, 1983 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Math/CS 448 Notebooks I & II, 1979-1980 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Math 448 Notebook, 1999 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Math Related Physics Articles, 1962-2006 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Arthur Matluck, Vector Integral Calculus, 1966-1998 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Minimal Sum of Surfaces of Revolution RS Chron, 1985 (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Articles, 1960-1983 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Articles, 1964-1974 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Articles, 1983 (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Computing Publications, 1996-2000 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Notes and Diagrams, 1982-2002 (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Physics Articles, 1992-1995 (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Physics Articles, 1967-1975 (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Physics Articles, 1976-1996 (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Publications Recruitment, 1994, 2004 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Research, 1977-1978 (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Modern Physics, 1993-2008 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Molecules/T.C. Devore, 1980-1981 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Montgomery, 1980 (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Montpelier Slave Descendants Reunion, 2007 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Philip Morrison Papers, 1993 (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Morrison's The Ring of Truth (Epilogue), Jenkins and MacDonald's "Science Teaching in the Spirit of Science", 1987, 1989 (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - N-body Paper, 2008-2009 (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - N-body Parallel Code, 2007-2010 (Box 59, Folder 10)
  - NC3 Manuscript, 1991-1993 (Box 59, Folder 11)
  - Navier-Stokes Eq. in Cylindrical & Polar Coordinates (tritton), undated (Box 59, Folder 12)
  - Newbridge Book Clubs, 1994 (Box 59, Folder 13)
  - Newsweek, 2005 (Box 59, Folder 14)
  - Thomas Nickles, "God Science as Bad History…", undated (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Non-linear dynamics & chaos background, 2001-2013 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Norbery: Vertebrate Flight, undated (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Notes, 1983, 1993 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Notes (notebook), 1978-1983 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Notes & Problems, 1975-1976 (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Notes on Woodward's History of Surgery, 1989 (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - Mark Ostrander's Work, 1981 (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - Nuclides File Project, 1980-1983 (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - Numerical Recipeson Runge-Kulta Integration, undated (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - Numerical Solution of Scattering Problems, 1975-1976 (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - Olbers' Paradox: 1) Ch.12 of Cosmology 2) Why the Sky is Dark at Night, 1981 (Box 60, Folder 12)
  - "On being a scientist," "10 Outstanding Achievements 1964-1989", 1989 (Box 60, Folder 13)
  - "One World or None", 1988 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Optics, 1976-1977 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Oscillations of a hanging chain, 1977 (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Oscillations of a hanging chain, 1977 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Oscillations of a hanging chain, 1977-1982 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - G. Edgar Parker and James S. Sochacki's "A Picard-McLauren Theorem for Initial Value PDE's," "Implementing the Picard Iteration", 1998 (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Paterson Problem Solutions, 1986 (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Penny Count, 2006-2008 (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - Periodic Table, undated (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - Photogrammetry, 1982-1986 (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - Physics & Biology, undated (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Physics degree stats, 1994-1998 (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - Phys Dept 1996-1997 Solar Wind Theory, undated (Box 61, Folder 13)
  - Physics Education & Physics Stats, 1994 (Box 61, Folder 14)
  - Physics History & People, 1973-1992 (Box 61, Folder 15)
  - Physics Nobelists, undated (Box 61, Folder 16)
  - Physics of Flying, 2002 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Physics Problems and Solutions, 1979-1980 (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - The Physics Teacher, 1994 (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - The Physics Teacher Submission, "A Consistent Sigh Convention for Work", 1987-2000 (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Physics Today, 1987 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Physics Today Book Review, 2002 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Physics Today Various Articles, 1982-1994 (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Physics Today Various Articles, 1982-1994 (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Planetarium Coor Trans, 1978-1979 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Poisson Distribution, 1980 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Polyhedra, 2009 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Potential Flow (Inviscid Flow), 2001 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Presidential Marches, 2007 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Princeton University Researchship Trip, 2009 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Problems & Notes, 1984-1985, 1998 (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - Problems from Den Hautog's Advanced Strength of Materials, 1986 (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - Projects, 1975 (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - QM Mechanics Oscillator, 1984 (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Quasars and radio galaxies misc. notes,, 1971-1975 (Box 63, Folder 11)
  - Radioactive Decay: P335, 1981 (Box 63, Folder 12)
  - Radio Astronomy (Fear), 1978 (Box 63, Folder 13)
  - Rainbow Theory, 1991-2004 (Box 63, Folder 14)
  - Rate of Ionization of Neutrals by a Thermal Distribution of Electrons, 1976-1977 (Box 63, Folder 15)
  - A.J.S. Rayl, "Popular Science Writing…," The Scientist, 1992 (Box 63, Folder 16)
  - Reading Guide & Comic, undated (Box 63, Folder 17)
  - Reading Material, 1992-1993 (Box 63, Folder 18)
  - Reading Memos Fall, 2008 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Record Book, 1975-1978 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Reference Formulaeon Vectors, 1979 (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - eitz, Milford, & Christy Solutions, 1987-1988 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - "Relativistic Rectlinear Rest-Rigid-Motions of Extended," outline, draft, & notes, 1982 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Republic of Letters annotated index, undated (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Rocket Science, 2003 (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Rocktown piece on James Madison, 2006 (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - "Rotating" Chain-Analytical, 1977 (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - Rotating Chain-Numerical, 1977 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Rotating Fluids & Rotating Frames (uniformly rotating fluids; internal forces; weather maps), 1999-2001 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Scales, ca, 1985 (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Schey, et. al. "A Laboratory, Computer and Calculus Based Course in Mathematics", 1969 (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Schey Solutions, 1992 (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Science and technology in James Madison's world, 2006-2007 (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Science education, 1987-1990 (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - Science is not enough, 1995 (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - Scientific computing note books, 1982, 1994 (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - Sep in Science & Tech Article RS Chron, 1987 (Box 65, Folder 10)
  - Serway & Faughn notes and solutions, undated (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Shaping the future: New Expectations for Undergraduate education in Science, Mathematics, Engineering, and Technology, 1996 (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Sigma Pi Sigma Sample Survey, 1994-1995 (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Sketychy notes & references, 1975 (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Smooth Particle Applied Mechanics (SPAM), 2000-2001 (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Smooth Particle Mechanics, 2001-2002 (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - Solar Physics Talk, 1969 (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - Solar Pulsations, 1974-1977 (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - Solutions & Notes, 1987 (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - Some Events in Science and Technology, 1945, 198, 1998 (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - Source Symmetry, 1975-1976 (Box 66, Folder 11)
  - Spectrum, 1992-1994 (Box 66, Folder 12)
  - Standards/Curves, 1975-1979 (Box 66, Folder 13)
  - Statistical Physics Book, 1977-1985 (Box 66, Folder 14)
  - Statistics of Identical Particles and Radioactive Decay: A Statistical Process Notes, 1981-2000 (Box 66, Folder 15)
  - Arthur Steinbergand Christopher Craig. "Technologies and Culture and Technologies in Historical Perspective", 1991 (Box 66, Folder 16)
  - Stella Structure, 1982-1985 (Box 66, Folder 17)
  - Stewart & Blair's 'Spiking neural network simulation…", 2009 (Box 66, Folder 18)
  - Strogatz figures, Ch. 1-7, undated (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Strogatz figures, Ch. 8-12, undated (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Summary of Activities (notebook), 1976-1978 (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Surface Force, Hydrostatic Pressure Stress Tensor & Navier-Stokes equation, undated (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - SX (Straight Xerox) file, 1982 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Syllabus Collection on Arms Control & Nuclear Issues P150, 1988 (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Symmetry & All That, 1993 (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - The Symmetry and Geometry of Double Radio Sources, 1975 (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - Table of Nuclear Properties (lightest Nuclei), 1981, undated (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - Talk on X-Ray Sky, 1976 (Box 67, Folder 10)
  - Taylor & Reiseman, 1979 (Box 67, Folder 11)
  - Edwin Taylor and David Reiseman, "What to Ask of a College", 1979 (Box 67, Folder 12)
  - "TBS" Gened Comm, 1994-1995, undated (Box 67, Folder 13)
  - Terrestrial Atmosphere & Gravitation, 1983 (Box 67, Folder 14)
  - Tethers & Catenaries (GMU April '02), 2002 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Text Notes, 1975 (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Theory of Ion Source, 1977 (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Thermodynamic Properties (Schroeder), 1982-1983 (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - "Tide Spring Revisited", 1988 (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Time's Arrow in Physics, 1977 (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Tobacco Research, 2007 (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - Transparencies, undated (Box 68, Folder 8)
  - Traveling Sound Waves in a Uniform Fluid: Summary, 1983 (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - George Trigg. "Crucial Experiments in Modern Physics", 1971 (Box 68, Folder 10)
  - Unger, et. al., "Monolithic Microgabricated Valves and Pumps by Multilayer Soft Lithography", 2000 (Box 68, Folder 11)
  - Unnamed Binder, 2000-2001, undated (Box 68, Folder 12)
  - URLs, 1999-2003 (Box 68, Folder 13)
  - Using History of Physics in Physics teaching, 1994 (Box 68, Folder 14)
  - UMSC overheads, 1994-1996 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - V/VM Tests, 1974 (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Video Resource Guide, undated (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Virginia Journal of Science, 1977 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Wadsworth Correspondence & forms, 1982-1984 (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - War of 1812 Project, 2012 (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - Weighted Dice Data, 1994 (Box 69, Folder 7)
  - Weisskopf's "The Significance of Science" from Physics in the Twentieth Century, 1972 (Box 69, Folder 8)
  - What to Ask of a College, 1979 (Box 69, Folder 9)
  - White dwarf data/talk, 1975-1976 (Box 69, Folder 10)
  - White dwarfs- Ingham, Brecher, & Wasserman, 1976 (Box 69, Folder 11)
  - White dwarfs: visuals, 1976 (Box 69, Folder 12)
  - John Wiley File, 1988-2004 (Box 69, Folder 13)
  - Women and minorities in math, 1991 (Box 69, Folder 14)
  - Word & Concept Lists, 1976-1978 (Box 69, Folder 15)
  - Working Folder, 1980-1983 (Box 69, Folder 16)
  - Working Paper on Symmetry Parameters of Double Radio Sources, 1975 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - World of Mathematics notes, undated (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - Writing File, 1983 (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - X-Ray Astronomy, 1976 (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Zirin, Ingham, Hudson, and McKenzie, Solar Physics, 1969 (Box 70, Folder 5)
- Series 4: JMU Departmental and JMU Materials, 1976-2012
  Scope and Contents
  Arranged in three subseries: 4.1. JMU Materials is arranged alphabetically, 4.2. Physics Department Materials is arranged alphabetically, and 4.3. Canadian Faculty Residency is arranged alphabetically.
  This series contains information pertaining Dr. Ingham's role in the JMU community and the physics department specifically. Dr. Ingham's time spent as a faculty-in-residence at Acadia University in Nova Scotia, Canada is also well-documented. The JMU materials include papers from JMU sponsored events and Dr. Ingham's role in JMU task forces and committees. For example, Dr. Ingham played a pivotal role in editing the faculty handbook as a member of the Faculty Handbook Task Force; related materials are included. Also included in this series are annual departmental evaluations, Dr. Ingham's personal faculty evaluations and performance reviews, and information pertaining to Ingham's tenure application. Of particular interest are the materials (including photographs) related to Physics Teaching Resource Agents (PTRA) – a summer institute at JMU to train rural high school physics teachers. Documents related to visiting scholars, lecturers, including Isaac Asimov who spoke at the 1979 Arts and Sciences Symposium, and various grant proposals are contained within this series. Dr. Ingham was awarded a major grant funded by the Appalachia Education Laboratory entitled "Interdisciplinary Science: Transforming Educational Experiences" (ISTEE) "to develop a college-level interdisciplinary physical science course that will satisfy JMU's general-education requirements and will be particularly appropriate for prospective middle school teachers." This series is organized into three subseries – 4.1. JMU Materials, 4.2. Physics Department Materials, and 4.3. Canadian Faculty Residency.
  - 4.1: JMU Materials, 1976-2012
    - Academic Affairs, 1990-1991 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Academic Program Reviews, 1998 (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Academic Initiatives Five-Year Plan, 1985-1989 (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - Blackboard 6.3 Updated, undated (Box 70, Folder 9)
    - Campus Flyers and Advising Materials, 1983-1998 (Box 70, Folder 10)
    - Centennial Strategic Plan, 2005 (Box 70, Folder 11)
    - CFI Materials, 2003-2008 (Box 70, Folder 12)
    - CIT Seminar: Technological Solutions to Teaching and Learning Challenges in the Classroom, 2006 (Box 70, Folder 13)
    - College of Letters and Sciences Materials, 1989-1992 (Box 70, Folder 14)
    - Commencement Program, 1998 (Box 70, Folder 15)
    - Commencement Program, 2009 (Box 70, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, JMU Presidential Search, 1998 (Box 70, Folder 17)
    - Faculty Handbook Taskforce, 1999-2001 (Box 70, Folder 18)
    - Faculty Handbook, 2001 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Faculty Meetings, 1993-1994 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Faculty Workshop Series, 2009 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - "Funding News and Notes", 2000 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Google Earth Sandbox, 2010 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Google Earth Sandbox-Madison, 2011 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Honors Program Awards Ceremony, 2002 (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - Honors Program Brown Bag Lecture Series, 1997 (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Interdisciplinary Science Major, 1989-1990 (Box 71, Folder 9)